<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Continental Reporters]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Continental Reporters]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/egerue-nnamdi/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 06:41:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/egerue-nnamdi/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/d9a8e1c6-ef35-4284-85b5-3abc7ec051bc.jpg" alt="ME ">]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/egerue-nnamdi/09b726c1-5bb2-43d0-8acf-4e34a2f855e4/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">09b726c1-5bb2-43d0-8acf-4e34a2f855e4</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 06:41:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Nigerian State]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ad2f18fd-b304-464a-9c47-45a8e6f9dcc2.jpg">]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/egerue-nnamdi/the-man-harold-smith-is-not-new-in-nigerian-history-he-is-o/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4670a8fd-1c51-4fcf-8c57-c9a38442b4c7</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 16:02:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Photos of clash between security and IPOB/MASSOB Eromosele Ebhomele 3 days ago 38600 Share on Facebook Share on Twitter Send email – Two weeks after a clash between Nigeria’s security operatives and pro-Biafra agitators, photographs of some killed members of the Indigenous People of Biafra (IPOB) and the Movement for the Actualization of the Sovereign State of Biafra (MASSOB) have surfaced. – The photographs show the magnitude of violence that took over a day supposedly to honour late Biafra warlord, Dim Odimegwu Ojukwu. READ ALSO: Biafra killings: We acted in self defence, Nigerian military says Recall that a day after the incident, about 88 members of MASSOB, who were arrested by the Ebonyi state police while they celebrated the day were arraigned. Share on Facebook Share on Twitter A victim of IPOB/police clash Share on Facebook Share on Twitter A victim of IPOB/police clash Share on Facebook Share on Twitter A victim of IPOB/police clash Share on Facebook Share on Twitter A victim of IPOB/police clash Share on Facebook Share on Twitter A victim of IPOB/police clash Share on Facebook Share on Twitter An expended bullet Share on Facebook Share on Twitter A victim of IPOB/police clash Share on Facebook Share on Twitter A victim of IPOB/police clash Share on Facebook Share on Twitter A victim of IPOB/police clash Share on Facebook Share on Twitter A victim of IPOB/police clash Since the clash, the agitators have remained angry accusing the government and its agencies of persecution. They recently described as traitors leaders of the Igbo race who visited President Muhammadu Buhari in the heat of the attack</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/egerue-nnamdi/photos-of-clash-between-security-and-ipobmassob-eromosele-e/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3d5ef0b9-5e34-4619-8383-35363191cdf3</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 06:15:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>MASSOB pledges support to Niger Delta Avengers Andrew Sweeney 1 week ago 254914 Share on Facebook Share on Twitter Send email – MASSOB has pledged its full allegiance to the Niger Delta Avengers – The pro-Biafra group has praised the militant group for its recent activities – The avengers has carried out a string of sabotage attacks in the region recently The Movement for the Actualization of the Sovereign State of Biafra (MASSOB) pledged its total allegiance to the Niger Delta Avengers on Saturday, along with other pro-Biafra groups operating in the Niger Delta region, the Daily Post has reported. The Niger Delta Avengers has carried out a series of bombings in the Niger Delta region and also threatened to assassinate President Muhammadu Buhari if he visited Ogoniland in Rivers state. Along with pledging allegiance to the militants, MASSOB is also demanding the release of Radio Biafra Director Nnamdi Kanu. Share on Facebook Share on Twitter MASSOB protests have become more frequent and vocal recently READ ALSO: IPOB lays shocking accusations against army, police In a statement signed by the national leader of MASSOB, Comrade Uchenna Madu, MASSOB is glad that the Avengers have shown consistent support for actualizing Biafra. “The consistency, selflessness and pragmatism of these Biafra warriors gladdens our hearts,” Madu said. “It shows and proves the positiveness [sic] and acceptability of Biafra by our brethren across the Niger. Share on Facebook Share on Twitter “It also rubbished the earlier diversionary, cowardice, stupid and negative comments, statements and positions of some leaders of ethnic nationalities of the South South who are being brainwashed by Hausa Fulani Yoruba oligarchies against Biafra. “The activities of the current warriors in the Niger Delta is a natural confirmation that Biafra stretches towards the gulf of Guinea. The natural inhabitants and indigenous people of these lands are Biafrans by birth but Nigeria by citizens.”</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/egerue-nnamdi/massob-pledges-support-to-niger-delta-avengers-andrew-sweene/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">882967d0-300d-45fe-8468-a0885d850a75</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 06:13:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>IPOB rejects Obiano's offer to pay Biafra agitator's bill Omotayo Yusuf 3 days ago 58999 Share on Facebook Share on Twitter Send email – IPOB has accused Governor Obiano of trying to get cheap popularity – The separatist group said it does not want the governor’s offer – An APC chieftain in Enugu also blamed the governor The Indigenous People Of Biafra (IPOB) has rejected the offer of Governor Wille Obiano of Anambra state to pay the hospital bills of Biafra agitators injured during their 49 years anniversary. Vanguard reports that the governor made the pledge at Nkpor town hall when he came to sympathize with the people of Nkpor. READ ALSO: MASSOB issues warning to Governor Obiano During the celebration of the declaration of Biafra on Monday, June 30, there was a clash between pro-Biafra agitators and the army which led to the death of some members of the separatist group while several others were injured. IPOB through its media and publicity officer Mr Emma Powerful dismissed the governor’s offer to offset the hospital bills of the wounded Biafra and non Biafra agitators and described the gesture as medicine after death and an attempt to win cheap popularity. “The governor was insulting the families of the dead Biafrans and those that their own are still nursing gunshot wounds in different hospitals and for the purpose of clarity, no gunshot wound victim is still in Anambra State, they have all been taken out of Anambra because the soldiers were combing all the hospitals in the state for them.” READ ALSO: MASSOB, BIM appeal to UN to divide Nigeria Chief Zeribe Ezeanuna who is a chieftain of the All Progressives Congress in the state faulted the governor for the clash. He demanded an apology from him and claimed that if he had not sanctioned the military engagement, it would not have been carried out. Meanwhile, IPOB has labelled Igbo elders who visited President Muhammadu Buhari as traitors. The elders visited the president in the wake of the clash that occurred between protesters and Biafra agitators. In a press statement signed by its coordinator, Clifford Iroanya, the group said it was surprised at the likes of those who rushed to Buhari and congratulated him for reportedly killing Biafrans on the fateful day and not to condemn his murderous act or to discuss the process of restoration of Biafra.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/egerue-nnamdi/ipob-rejects-obianos-offer-to-pay-biafra-agitators-bill-om/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">008202f3-9aab-4807-9ab7-2beae2ff84f9</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 06:10:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Drink your oil, we would eat our yams, Arewa chieftain tells Niger Delta ON JUNE 5, 20169:07 PMIN NEWS, POLITICSCOMMENTS Senator Joseph Kennedy N Waku, (JKN Waku), the stormy petrel of the Middle Belt was elected senator for the Benue North West Constituency of Benue State, on the platform of the Peoples Democratic Party, PDP in 1999. Not long after she came into national renown following his controversial call for a military coup on the claim that President Olusegun Obasanjo was derailing the democracy project. Since then he has been an unrepentant critic of President Obasanjo, and a major political figure in the North. Waku is not only a chieftain of the ruling All Progressives Congress, APC but also of the Arewa Consultative Forum, ACF. In this interview, he speaks on current national issues. Excerpts: By Joseph Erunke What is your reaction to the renewed insurgency by militants in the Niger Delta? In the first place, what were the offences committed by these people before they were pardoned? Are they not criminals? If I were the president, I would jail them. So, are you ruling out dialogue as proposed by some people as a way of resolving the problem? What kind of dialogue? Let them bring to table what they want. Let them do what they are doing, they will also suffer it. Are they also not suffering when they ruin the economy? Are they not facing the same problem like you and I? They are talking of marginalization today. If you create Biafra today, is Biafra solidly Igbo’s? It’s not. When you go there, you would find a southern minority who will tell you that they don’t want to be part of it, even among the Igbo. Some Igbo will tell you that they don’t want it. If there is definitive kind of discrimination against certain segments of the country, that needs to be addressed because injustice creates dissatisfaction. If there have been injustices against one particular group in this country, let’s address it and not by taking the law into their hands. That is criminality. We are also affected but we want to take it in a matured approach. You cannot go and begin to destroy state apparatus in order to achieve your agitation, it is against the law. I am not in a position to talk about which contract was revoked because I am not involved in that. If those contracts were illegally awarded without going through the due process and the current administration wants to follow due process, what is bad about that? Go and do your investigation on that contract to see whether the old law that qualifies one for such contracts were made. What do you award contracts to militants for? In the first place, the name ‘militant’ is criminality. It is only this country that somebody will come back and say I am a militant and then ‘you award him contract.’ If they claim to be agitators as they are saying, then let them come out with their demands and not by holding the state to ransom. Now, how would you want the government to handle this situation? My advice is that you can’t take government for ransom. If their livelihoods have been damaged considerably by the pipelines and they have nowhere to go, let there be adequate compensation to them. It is not to take laws into their hands. And by the way, let me be honest with you, this is natural resources; nobody owns it and nobody farms it but by virtue of the location that you find yourself. If there is ecological diversification and you need to do something for your livelihood, then you table this issue to the federal government so that there would be amicable resolution Giving the adverse effects of their actions, will it not be better to seek dialogue? What do they need? Let them come out and tell government that ‘this has been our farmland, it has been devastated, we have no land to farm anymore’ and then bring a proposal to the federal government. This is how it should be done than issuing threats. If I were the president, I would have ended that thing by now. How would you have done it? Yes, by closing the whole thing down. Before oil came, didn’t this country exist? So, what are you talking about? We have been blindfolded and Nigeria became so lazy, a nation of cheap money. Before the oil, we had cocoa, we had palm oil, groundnut and pyramid, and those were the things that actually helped to develop the oil. At a point, we in Benue challenged them that okay,’ let them go and drink their oil, we would eat our yams and then see who will survive.’ Read full interview on Monday Vanguard</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/egerue-nnamdi/drink-your-oil-we-would-eat-our-yams-arewa-chieftain-tells/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5366a6df-cc8b-4ddf-a77f-9758d52f024b</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 06:08:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Nigerian army justified the killing pro-Biafra supporters on May 30 – The army claimed that soldiers acted in self-defence when their intervention to restore law and order was resisted – Nigerians took to social media to express their indignation and discontent Share on Facebook Share on Twitter The Nigerian army has recently explained why the soldiers were forced to kill some activists who were commemorating Biafra day in some parts of the country. Justifying the action, Colonel Hamza Gambo, the deputy director of army public relations, 82 Division, Nigerian Army, Enugu, said that soldiers acted in self-defence when their intervention to restore law and order was resisted. “Instructively, troops of 82 Division Nigerian Army as the lead agency of the security agencies had to invoke the extant Rules of Engagement (ROE) to resort to self-defence, protection of the strategic Niger Bridge, prevent re-enforcement of the pro-Biafran members apparently surging ahead from the far side of the strategic Niger Bridge at Onitsha. “In the aftermath of the fire fight that ensued, many of our troops sustained varying degree of injuries. The injured troops are currently receiving treatment at our medical centre. Similarly, five members of MASSOB/IPOB were killed, eight wounded while nine were arrested for due legal actions,” he said. READ ALSO: Biafra massacre: 53 killed, 207 wounded, 403 arrested Following the army’s statement, Nigerians took to social media to express their indignation and discontent.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/egerue-nnamdi/nigerian-army-justified-the-killing-pro-biafra-supporters-on/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">fdb92868-7013-462b-ae55-da55380e5ce7</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 06:05:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Federal Government Is Not Treating Igbo People Right - Yerima Lucky Vincent 7 months ago 209687 Share on Facebook Share on Twitter Send email Alhaji Shettima Yerima, an activist and president of the Arewa Youth Consultative Forum (AYCF) in this interview, blows hot about the way the people of the South-eastern part of Nigeria have been treated by the government, and why he thinks the agitation for Biafra is justified even though it is not the best option. The fiery leader of the AYCF also suggests solutions to the crisis. Share on Facebook Share on Twitter Alhaji Shettima Yerima, a activist and president of the Arewa Youth Consultative Forum How did this agitation come this far? Well, it’s been a very long journey and for people like us, it is not surprising. The agitation for Biafra is not news to us because it has been there over time especially since 1966 with what gave birth to the overthrow of the Aguiyi Ironsi government after the killing of some top leaders. The agitation has been there and that was what led to civil war in 1967 when Odimegwu Ojukwu came on board against the state and the reconciliation in the 1970s. Ever since, there had always been one agitation of the other. But the truth of the matter is that nobody is happy about the situation and all of us felt that it would not augur and it is not even in the best interest of this country for any part to secede now. This is a critical and very challenging time. And it is high time we began looking at the issue critically. We are only pretending that Nigeria is a nation, it has never been a nation. We just pray that it would become a nation. There are very fundamental issues that need to be addressed by any government in place and, to do that we must apply the principles of equity, justice and fairness to all. The moment we begin to say this group of people must be dealt with decisively because of their mindset or thinking that they are being marginalised, then there is a problem. READ ALSO: Gowon Slams Biafra Agitators The government must be seen to be doing justice and discussing issues the way they are. If we continue to pretend that things are normal and people are saying they are not normal and are agitating, one day it might not be funny. In as much as we pretend that things are well, you can see this call for Biafra is getting more popular internationally. I pray and I pray the leaders begin to see reasons to look at the issues critically. If they feel they are being marginalised and you underestimate and threaten them by arresting them and incarcerating them, just know that the more you do that, the more they get international and local sympathy. At the end of the day, you would be marvelled at what that amounts to. It could metamorphose into something beyond your expectation. Detention and arrests are not the answers to the issue. Issues must be brought forward for discussion. We must disagree to agree so that we can form a nation. We are not yet a nation. Under international laws which Nigeria is signatory to, the right to see for nationhood is guaranteed. Thus, if people decide that they don’t want to be part of your project, there is nothing you can do about it. Whatever you do is just to buy time. So why don’t you look at the issues the way they are and address them once and for all? This is what I think and it is absolutely my opinion. Those sympathetic to President Muhammadu Buhari believe that the agitation became intense because the average Igbo man does not like a Hausa man being the President. Do you subscribe to this? I do not subscribe to that because before Buhari, there were leaders who came from the Nort. Umar Yar’Adua was from the North and we could see the support from the East until lately when there was this problem of misgivings just before the recent elections. The perception of those in the camp of President Buhari is that the South-east was against him and that he did not get enough votes from the area and so what they bargained for is what they would get. Again, I do not share that perception. This is because this is a democracy where everyone has the right to decide where he wants to stay and if a government is finally formed at the end of the day, that government must be seen to be all-inclusive and carry everybody along irrespective of whether you got votes or not. You must be seen to be more civilised and behave in very civil ways so that we will all feel we are part of this democracy. But where things went wrong and you want to pay back, I do not think that is nationalistic. And when the issue of appointments came up and some positions that should be shared nationally went in one direction as far as we were concerned, some of us raised alarm we did not raise alarm because we don’t enjoy Buhari, but because we know he is human and those who work with him are also human. So where something is going wrong, there is no problem in calling the person to correct it. I do not think it is in the best interest of Nigerians to play politics with things like this because the only reason Buhari is elected is because people gave him mandate to be President of Nigeria and so issues of a section of the country not giving him their votes should not arise. The perception became more glaring and visible because certain things happened in recent times, especially just before the election, after the election and in appointments. It is not because they hate Buhari but certain things have gone wrong and it is better to address them. As long as they remain part of the country, what belongs to them must be given. But where we believe that some parts of the country should be treated as second-class citizens, then we are not doing justice to the nation or that we want the country to survive. This is just the truth of it. There is also this argument that the South-east is not ripe enough to call for secession because there is not particular leader to take them out of the woods. An analyst recently cited the case of South Sudan. What do you think? That they are not mature enough, how is that our problem, the problem of anybody or a section of the country? By law, how is that a problem? It is either you decide to carry them along or if you feel they are a burden to you, then allow them to go. When a child decides that it is time to come out of her mummy’s womb, you can’t stop the child. Oftentimes, we make the mistake of comparing Nigeria with other countries forgetting that we do not share the same culture. We are people from different backgrounds, religions and environments. So I do not share that sentiment. There are also countries that broke and the seceding countries are living on their own. Have you ever seen where a country breaks up and the parts come back together because it was a mistake? It has never happened. So who is afraid in the case of Nigeria? If we cannot do justice to all, then let everyone go peacefully. For me, I do not think the entire North should be held responsible for not allowing the East to go. For me, if they choose to go, so be it. The day we fee tired of this project called Nigeria, we too in the North would say we are going. Let nobody hold anybody to ransom. I only just think going our separate ways is not the best answer, but let’s also begin to decide for them as if we should tell what they want or not. If we cannot bring equity and justice to this table and discuss it, then what is the essence of this pretence? We don’t have to pretend; the country is sick and we need a man who truly believes in the nation to govern it rather than heating it up. And this is where I differ because with the problem at hand like insurgency in the northern part of the country, there should not be any reason to create another monster in another part of the country. Leaders must be seen to be low-headed at this time. Let us not be fooled, this is the best time for leaders to put their heads together and see how things would be solved and appreciate the fact that we come from different backgrounds. Let us not abuse this opportunity. If found wanting, let us address the problem and stop behaving like there is no problem. The moment you begin to say some people should be sidelined, then you are not bargaining for peace. READ ALSO: Radio Biafra Director Granted Bail In resolving this problem now, do you suggest that the report of the last National Conference should be looked into? The report of the National Conference cannot be a reason to start looking at a new Nigeria because even some of us have issues with the Confab and its composition and how it went. This government must be open because if we cannot sit down and discuss it, then there is a problem. This government must be create an atmosphere and engage everyone. I believe a Sovereign National Conference is the answer to this whole thing and there must be no no-go area. People must be allowed to discuss issues. Often, when the issues of national discourse emerge, these mischief makers, these crooks who are 80 percent criminally-minded people at the National Assembly would tell you that they are the ones to discuss them. You cannot be the manager of Nigeria because they voted for you. You cannot just wake up one morning and declare that the sovereignty of the people is now your own. Allow the rightful owners decide how they want to live together and move forward. The constitution we have today is fraud. We challenge the legality of the preamble of the constitution. You cannot be move a country forward where there is problem. The country is sick! We can only buy time, but the day it would escalate, everyone would start running helter-skelter. And I am afraid that the prediction of America that Nigeria would break would not come to pass. Unfortunately, the government of the day believes so much in America. In fact, they even consult America before introducing some local policies to us. You can see how bad it is that after 55 years, Nigeria has not grown enough to decide how we want to govern ourselves. Must we consult America? Why can’t we do our thing our own way? Who even tells you America is in support of Nigerians uniting together? History has shown that so many wars and insurgency around the world have the imprint of America. Can’t we learn from history? Do we want to go into another civil war? I can tell you that if Nigeria goes into another civil war now, we will not survive it.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/egerue-nnamdi/federal-government-is-not-treating-igbo-people-right-yerim/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">01f42d0e-8b29-456b-a423-b88ddb365ce3</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 05:57:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Governor Ayodele Fayose of Ekiti State has hailed the international community, especially the United States of America and the United Kingdom for joining lovers of democracy in Nigeria to speak out against the All Progressives Congress (APC) government of President Muhammadu Buhari’s use of State security apparatus to oppress opposition. He called on the British Government to investigate the allegation of the use of British foreign aid given to Nigeria to help combat Boko Haram terrorists to fund a witch-hunt against opposition politicians with a view to preventing continuous use of fund belonging to the country wrongly. Ayodele Fayose Speaking through Lere Olayinka, his Special Assistant on Public Communications and New Media, Governor Fayose said the international community must focus attention on Nigeria under President Buhari, saying; “rights of Nigerians are now being trampled upon with impunity.” In its report, the United States Department of States, accused the Nigerian police, DSS and the military of gross abuse of power which include citizens brutality, arbitrary detention,bribery among other scandals Also, the United Kingdom based Telegraph newspaper published this week that hundreds of millions of pounds of British foreign aid given to Nigeria to help combat Boko Haram terrorists was instead being used to fund a witch-hunt against opposition politicians. Governor Fayose, who is presently in Guangzhou, China to attend the 119th China Import and Export Fair otherwise known as the Canton Fair between April 14 and 19, said the United Kingdom Telegraph newspaper was right in its report that the Buhari’s government was using British aid money to target his political opponents, particularly through anti corruption agencies ans the Department of State Services (DSS). He said only the international community could help prevail on President Buhari to respect the rule of law and stop ruling Nigeria like a military dictator. The governor described the United States Department of States report as another vindication of his position on the Buhari-led government’s abuse of the rights of Nigerians, saying; “everything I predicted about Buhari is coming to pass and the international community must assist the country to sustain democracy.”</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/egerue-nnamdi/e98b4164-96c2-417b-80c0-8c0b3e1589c8/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">e98b4164-96c2-417b-80c0-8c0b3e1589c8</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 23:18:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>A movement, New Igbo Vision in APC Lagos has called on Igbo people in Lagos State to re-establish the harmonious relationship that existed between them and their hosts in Lagos. The group regretted the acrimony which created the impression that Ndigbo were at loggerheads with their hosts and other ethnic nationalities in Lagos. Addressing a joint press conference in Lagos, the APC Publicity Secretary in Lagos and Eze Ndigbo in Lagos, Messrs Joe Igbokwe and Eze Uche Dimgba respectively, appealed to Igbos in Lagos “who are passionate towards promoting progressive politics and the interest of Ndgbo to key in to this noble idea and join in rebuilding a badly damaged bridge that have hitherto contributed immensely to the huge and monumental successes Ndigbo have made in Lagos.”   29 0 1</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/egerue-nnamdi/d79f7adc-b7ab-497b-be93-923dad6fd6e7/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">d79f7adc-b7ab-497b-be93-923dad6fd6e7</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 23:14:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>