<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Continental Reporters]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Continental Reporters]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/egerue-nnamdi/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 21:42:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/egerue-nnamdi/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 21:42:31 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/fc41c2861a26afb77a5c9dbb278f6f4aa1f36ae6.jpg">,<p>Erstwhile Minister of Finance, Dr. Ngozi Okonjo-Iweala, has blamed the country’s present economic situation on the zero political will of the immediate past government to save for the rainy day. Speaking, yesterday, at the George Washington University, Washington D.C. Okonjo-Iweala said the Goodluck Jonathan administration differed seriously from the Olusegun Obasanjo administration under whose administration the Nigeria government saved $22 billion, which she said, helped to cushion the dryness that came the way of the country at the end of the last decade. Okonjo-Iweala served as finance minister under President Obasanjo between 2003 and 2006 and again under President Jonathan between 2011 and 2015. The former finance minister and World Bank president, who spoke on “inequality, growth and resilience,” with Chile as an example of a country with a saving culture, was quoted by The Cable, an online news medium, to have said: *Ngozi-Okonjo-Iweala “We tried it in Nigeria, we put in an oil price based fiscal rule in 2004 and it worked very well. “We saved $22 billion because the political will to do it was there. And when the 2008 /2009 crisis came, we were able to draw on those savings precisely to issue about a five per cent of GDP fiscal stimulus to the economy, and we never had to come to the Bank or the Fund. “This time around and this is the key now, you need not only to have the instrument, but you also need the political will. In my second time as a finance minister, from 2011 to 2015, we had the instrument, we had the means, we had done it before, but zero political will. “So we were not able to save when we should have. That is why you find that Nigeria is now in the situation it is in. Along with so many other countries. “That is the question that I ask, what do we need to do to these countries to save over a period of long accelerated growth. “We need to devise mechanisms not just that are good technically but find a way to either embed them in the constitution or find a way to separate them from the political manipulation so that these countries can survive over time. “To build resilience, African countries need tools, mechanisms and it is doable and we need to interrogate ourselves why we have not done it.” The Cable further quoted her as saying that manufacturing was also critical to growth in Nigeria and the rest of Africa as she was reported to have said that manufacturing represented just 11 per cent of GDP in Africa. “I do not believe that we can be resilient, except if we can encourage manufacturing even on the goods we consume, services, entertainment industry, agriculture. “I think these are the kinds of questions that policy makers struggle with on a daily basis and that is what we are going to answer to get resilience. “If we don’t get these mechanisms, we politicise them, find ways to transform the base of the economy and create jobs including in manufacturing, I believe we are going to go into this looming deceleration that is being talked about.” 1171 3 3 0</p>,<p>Read more at: http://www.vanguardngr.com/2016/04/nigeria-had-no-political-will-to-save-under-jonathan-okonjo-iweala/</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/egerue-nnamdi/ce82c03e-cf26-47e3-8e01-7aa05245d3ec/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ce82c03e-cf26-47e3-8e01-7aa05245d3ec</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 09:51:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former FIFA president Sepp Blatter told AFP Friday he “is available” to appear as a witness at a United States trial into mass corruption at world football’s ruling body. Blatter “Yes. When they need me to defend FIFA, I will be available,” Blatter said,]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://imgflo.herokuapp.com/graph/vahj1ThiexotieMo/7ec151eb2d1e45bae034b8cae84d272c/croprotate.jpg?cropheight=3600&cropwidth=2159&degrees=0&input=https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/d9a8e1c6-ef35-4284-85b5-3abc7ec051bc.jpg&x=0&y=0" alt="ME ">,<ul><li><em>Former FIFA president Sepp Blatter told AFP Friday he “is available” to appear as a witness at a United States trial into mass corruption at world football’s ruling body. Blatter “Yes. When they need me to defend FIFA, I will be available,” Blatter said, when asked if he would be prepared to attend the trial into the sweeping bribery scandal that has sparked an unprecedented crisis in world football. US prosecutors were hoping the hearing of 39 officials and marketing executives accused of soliciting and receiving tens of millions of dollars in bribes and kickbacks would begin in February 2017. But on Thursday, the US judge overseeing the corruption scandal postponed setting a trial date until after prosecutors share the bulk of evidence being collated in the massive investigation. Blatter, with European football chief Michel Platini, was banned from all football activities for eight years in December over an infamous two million Swiss franc ($2 million, 1.8 million euro) payment Platini received in 2011 from the then-FIFA president. The suspensions were cut to six years in February. Blatter, since replaced as FIFA president by Gianni Infantino, is awaiting a date for an appeal against his ban to the Court of Arbitration for Sport (CAS). Platini was told Friday his CAS appeal will be heard on April 29. Blatter commented: “It’s good news that CAS has made progress with Platini’s case. I think my case will be handled shortly after.” The 80-year-old Swiss added: “I believe that now, finally, at CAS, they are going to talk about justice, and not just speculation. “That means it’s justice that will o if the accused is guilty and not the accused who has to prove his innocence.” Irrespective of the outcome of his CAS hearing, Blatter plans to attend the 2018 World Cup finals in Russia as a guest of Russian President Vladimir Putin, although if he were to attend a match he would be flouting the terms of his suspension. “I’ve got an invitation to go to Russia,” he said. “I will go Russia. Going to Russia doesn’t mean that I’m going to watch games. They can’t stop me travelling. I go where I want to.”</em></li></ul>,<p><em>Read more at: http://www.vanguardngr.com/2016/04/blatter-available-defend-fifa-us-corruption-trial/</em></p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/egerue-nnamdi/09b726c1-5bb2-43d0-8acf-4e34a2f855e4/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">09b726c1-5bb2-43d0-8acf-4e34a2f855e4</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 08:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Nigerian State]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ad2f18fd-b304-464a-9c47-45a8e6f9dcc2.jpg">,<ul><li><em><strong>An Open Letter to My Brethren in the Southsouth – by Donald Ekpo “….for as long as the Old Eastern Region remains in disarray and not united, self-determination for the region will remain impossible….” – An anonymous retired Nigerian Army Chief The word “south-south”, even though it may sound absurd, is a name we have come to accept as a people. We can’t say exactly how we came about to be identified with the name neither can we say exactly when we were given the name, but we just know it is our name. While growing up back in the days, geography taught us about “the North”, “the South”, “The East” and “The West”. For proper definition of locations, we were also told about “The Northwest, Northeast, Southwest and Southeast” I can’t remember anything like the “Northnorth”, “Southsouth”, “Easteast” or Westwest , but here I am today, writing a letter to my Southsouth brethren. That is what happens to a people who are not in control of their cultural development or their political and economic future. That is what happens to a people who are just there for their numbers; that is what happens to people who are just kept for their services; that is what happens to people who are just custodians of wealth for a supposedly superior people and finally, that is what happens to people who are seen as slaves. Any name is suitable for them, they can only get whatever is given to them even if it is originally theirs. If in doubt, please remind me the meaning of KUNTA KINTE. A voice for the voiceless Daniel Ekpo hails from ethnic nationality of the Niger Delta I write this letter, not because it is frustrating to see how we allowed a defrauded propaganda to position our people as the pawns in the political chess game called Nigeria, but rather, I write this letter in an effort to request that we free ourselves from these propaganda that have lingered for too long. If our grandfathers and fathers did not ask questions, is there any divine law that says we cannot ask? We know we all belonged to the old Eastern Region of Nigeria before the Northern protectorate took back their power after the gruesome murder of General Aguiyi Ironsi. Just for the records, let me do us a bit of history here. Major General Ironsi, as Head of State, was cornered and arrested somewhere in Western Nigeria on July 29th of 1966, his hands and feet were tied together, then tied to a Land Rover jeep with a little space in between and driven on a tarred road, face down for several kilometers. The then highest ranking Northern officer, an acting (unconfirmed) lieutenant-colonel, was chosen to be the next Head of State ahead of serving brigadiers, colonels and lieutenant-colonels of Southern Nigeria, followed by the dreadful killings of officers and soldiers of Eastern Nigeria, including our so-called Southsouth soldiers and officers . The genocide that followed is what is recorded as the Nigerian Civil War of 1967–1970. As if that was not enough, the Eastern Region was broken apart with the sudden creation of the then Southeastern state (today’s Cross River and Akwa Ibom), Rivers State (today’s Rivers State and Bayelsa) and Eastcentral State (today’s Southeast geopolitical zone). It was during that war that propaganda were designed, created and generated to separate us from the old Eastern Region and to make the average Igbo man our potential enemy in an effort to reduce their own presumed enemies. In as much as it is a bitter history, I still find it necessary to provide you with this preamble. I write this letter to remind us that our region, known as the Southsouth today was a creation of the North for the sake of creating the disunity we face today. And more so, it was not just for the disunity for them to win the war, but to also take away our resources, our manpower and our economic future. In 2014, when President Jonathan, a son of the so called Southsouth, decided to re-contest the 2015 elections, Sheik Junaid Mohammed, in an engagement on behalf the Northern protectorate, reminded us that the so-called Southsouth was a creation of the North for effective management of the Northern interest in Eastern Nigeria. How bad could this be? Can we imagine that? So, while we are busy reminding ourselves that we are a different people or that the Igbos are wicked and are trying to kill us, the North is joyously taking over and owning 85% of our oil wells while the West takes the leftovers. And what do we get? Noise! Even the supposed football legend, Sunday Okechukwu Oliseh, is busy telling us he is not Igbo as if it is a curse to be Igbo. One wonders if the name “Okechukwu” is of Hausa or Yoruba origin. When you speak Igbo as a language and yet claim you are not Igbo, is that not the saddest thing that can happen to any people of identical culture? Even Major Kaduna Nzeogwu that led the first coup that was said to be an Igbo coup is from Okpanam village in today’s Delta State. Could he have come out to say today, like Sunday Oliseh said, that he was not Igbo? If the Abakaliki or Nsukka indigene who has a more distant dialect of Igbo is Igbo, how come the Anioma or Okrika indigene, whose dialect is easily understood, is not Igbo? How did a people of the same culture get so separated this far? Starvation used as instrument of war by Nigeria More than two million children, pregnant mothers and the aged died from malnutrition &amp; disease in civil-war Biafra I write this letter to speak to those of us regarded as minority tribes. How can we be minority when, in essence, we are known to be about 35 million of the said 180 million of the estimated population of Nigeria? How can we be a minority in our own lands if we were not treated as such or if we did not accept to be such? If those from the alliance which separated us from the West are said to be about 50 million in population and our brethren in the East are said to be about 40 million, how can we accept that we are a minority? Our compatriots from the alleged minorities of the North are said to be another 30 million. Who then is the minority? Having run through these figures, we know who the real minorities are. Be it as it appears, the truth is that our region was broken into two so as to weaken our original strength given that, at a combined population strength of 35 million plus 40 million people, our economic and entrepreneurial strength put together, would be something the ruling alliance will be worried about. So why should we ever think that it is logical to claim we are two different peoples when, in essence, we have always been one and the same people for over 1,000 years before the arrival of the white man? If what the white man did to us was not bad enough, is it not ridiculous that we allowed a certain minority made up of immigrants from fringes of the Sahara Desert to assume control of our economic and political future? I write this letter to ask my brethren in the Southsouth these pertinent questions. Let us assume the very worst situation in this supposed fracas between us and our Igbo brothers. Why are we worried about the Igbos taking over our “natural resources”, (assuming they don’t have theirs); ARE WE PRESENTLY IN CONTROL OF OUR “NATURAL RESOURCES”? Does it make more sense that our natural resources are being controlled by some strange people from over 700 miles away? The same people that kill us at will at any single provocation of their religion? People who even kill us in our land? People who challenge us to the ownership of these our very own resources? People who show absolute disregard for who we are? People who think it is a privilege for us to be in any position of authority? And finally, people who do not, in any way, have the kind of entrepreneurial skills that we have? Why would we allow our imaginary quarrel or fights with our brothers next-door to translate into the decision of one of the women in King Solomon’s judgment who insisted that, since she couldn’t have the contested child, the other woman should not either? The living and spirits of the dead share as one Colorful masquerade of the Niger Delta in a celebratory outing . So are we, in essence, saying it is better for none of us brethren to own our resources simply because we don’t trust our brothers, yet we do nothing about the strangers who have ripped us apart? Are we logically correct in believing this senseless fabricated quarrel? Even while we are senselessly worried about how the Igbos will colonize our people because that is what we were told and that is what some in the ruling alliance are still trying to tell us, can we sincerely tell ourselves that the Igbos are that evil? Evil enough to leave their own natural resources in Abia, Imo, Anambra, Ebonyi and Enugu states to come and take ownership of our own resources? How will they do that? How possible will it be for a people that barely kill by the sword to be compared to our present oppressors from up North? Do we honestly see that as a possibility? How and why did we allow these propaganda to go this far? Is this not what the hegemonic alliance has used to rule us through the divide-and-rule scheme? Sheik Jumiad Mohammed said it clearly that our separation was a creation of the North for the effective management of our regional resources while we keep fighting an imaginary enemy. I write this letter to remind us that we and our Igbo brothers, sisters, mothers and fathers have cultural identities, we uphold life to be sacrosanct, we do not kill a man like a chicken, we worship the same God and we have identical looks and reasoning capabilities. Education is a respected virtue to both of us and entrepreneurship is a common love between us. We both respect constituted authorities. Even though we both have some cultural oddities in our midst, that cannot and should not be used to castigate an entire people. So how come the Igbo man suddenly became evil shortly before the war if the castigation was not a propaganda tool of that war? How did we accept that our Igbo brothers were evil while we were saints? How are we saints? Is there any evil that is the monopoly of the Igbos which we are totally clean of? That we don’t have a single man/woman who does same if positioned in the same situation? How did we allow a distant people determine how we live our lives together with our very own neighbors? If we think that we are different and as such, we are treated better than the Igbos, have we noticed that the fate of the Onitsha Port is the same fate that befell the Ports in Calabar and Port Harcourt? We from the East are all forced to use the Lagos wharves in order to pay taxes to those who control this port. How have we been treated differently by the ruling alliance if we were different from the Igbos? Are we not facing the same fate as our Eastern brethren? How do you think we will fare if we were the only ones to receive this maltreatment, given a circumstance where the Igbos are no more in this contraption called Nigeria? I write this letter to our brethren to remind us that, without a unified stand by the entire region, the self-determination process will be a farce. We need each other in all difficulties. We are the Eastern Region; we are the region of the Lower Niger; we are a common people; we are not different from each other. Starting from the Hills of Ogoja to the rocky soils of Ebonyi, down to the temperate region of Anambra to the enclaves of Ishekiri and Isoko, we all look alike. The Akwa Ibom man and the Abia State man are the same people simply divided by boundaries. The Calabar man and the Arochukwu man has identical ancestral masquerades. The Ikwerre man is just an Igbo man that was separated by the North to act as a different people. A British woman, camped somewhere in Kaduna, decided to add the “R” consonant to the “U” vowel to “totally break the identities of the Igbos in today’s Rivers state”. The Ijaws, Kalabris, Oron and Efik are practically the same people positioned in different locations possibly during the settlements that happened centuries ago. We are all interrelated in the region and as such, must not be divided. We have been used for decades and disregarded at every opportunity; our rights are perceived as privileges, if not favors. We do not have control over our future as clearly stated by the late Alhaji Amadu Bello when he instructed his people not to allow us have control of our future, and that our ancestral lands should instead be seen as a conquered territory. Are we a conquered people by some strange fortune hunters who believe they are born to rule, conquer and kill? These are people who do not hold as sacrosanct what we revere as one. How can we continue in this union which was designed to enslave us? How can we allow the lies told by these strangers to pitch us against our very own selves? An Addendum to My Igbo Brothers Lower Niger circa 1885-1905 Map of Lower Niger territory before Amalgamation of 1914 I write to you to remind you that you can only fight a lie which was embedded into the hearts of my brethren by putting yourself in our shoes to know how best to respond. We cannot fight evil with evil. Like we know, they say two wrongs don’t make a right. It is your responsibility to subtly ask those accusing you some logical questions that may prick their hearts back to reality. We are all in this mess called Nigeria together. Our Son, Goodluck Jonathan, was treated the same way General Ironsi was treated; they were both rejected. They were both despised. Both of them wanted a united Nigeria that existed beyond tribes and religion. But what did we see? President Goodluck Jonathan was lucky to escape with his life, but General Ironsi was not that lucky. He was tied to a Land Rover jeep and driven on the rocky tarred roads between Abeokuta and Ibadan till he died and was shredded to pieces. Based on the Alhaji and Kunle’s phone conversation (https://goo.gl/8NhP7H) which I believe we all listened to, we know that it could as well have happened to President Jonathan if he was not wise enough to let go of their birth right. But can we continue like this? Look at what they are doing to Nnamdi Kanu? These are the same people who organized 70 lawyers to represent the Boko Haram suspects who have raped, maimed and killed Nigerians. “Yet the one they choose to lead us”, says Nnamdi, “is too dangerous to be released because he has dual citizenship.”? Is this the kind of place to which we shall continue to belong when we are likely going to be having malicious morons of this magnitude leading us? I write to you my brothers to remind you that the Gambaris know for certainty that, having broken a greater part of you into other states in the Southsouth, it may be difficult to successfully secede knowing what we know today. So it is inappropriate for you to remind my own brothers that with or without us, that you will succeed. We cannot allow the propaganda of these gambaris to keep us apart. We must reject it by all means and efforts. We stand a greater chance to succeed as one region. As the older one of the two broken parts of our region, it is your responsibility to expose the deception that was used to mislead my people. It is you who should tell my people that you do not have any intentions to colonize them. We have to collectively put this ruling alliance to shame by consciously keeping our relationship cordial in the region. My dear brethren, I write to request that you should regard it as a solemn duty to remind us that we are all one people because, in truth, WE ARE ONE. Regionalism with local autonomy is the way forward Movement for New Nigeria (MNN) agreed to above map to be future federations for a devolved Nigeria. The Lower Niger Congress (LNC) would not succeed if we do not position ourselves for success. We cannot go to a Referendum with a divided house. We have to all agree that we cannot continue in this contraption called a unitary Nigeria that was not just built on lies and propaganda, but was also designed to fail while it enslaves our people. We have been battered, raped, disregarded, maimed and killed at will for the past 50 years. I am talking about the entire Eastern Region. While we are being raped and killed, we are busy seeing each other as our own enemies while the real enemies smile at our folly. We cannot continue like this. We should all take the opportunity presented to us by the 2007 United Nations Declaration on Rights of Indigenous Peoples (UNDRIP) to free our peoples, once and for all. The LNC has, so far, made presentations to the US Congress on the plight of our peoples, made a presentation to the United Nations and have been able to secure a period by which the Referendum will take place here in our own region. But will we succeed during the electoral process if we are not united? Is it not time we beat our swords into plowshares and see how we can take control of our political and economic future as well as restore our cultural togetherness? The Lower Niger Congress, having met with traditional and titled leaders in all the corners of the Lower Niger territory, believes that our self-redemptive project will not be a success if we do not see ourselves as a united body. We cannot afford to go into a Referendum that could be sabotaged by the propaganda of the ruling alliance contrived by the North to keep all of us perpetually in bondage. It is our duty to educate ourselves, educate our relatives and educate our very own brethren in all nooks and crannies of the Lower Niger. It is the best duty we can do for future generations of our region yet unborn . This contraception called Nigeria was never designed to succeed; not with the present fraud of a constitution; not with the present mentality that only a section of the country is meant to rule eternally and finally, not with the present odds stacked up against our folks who make it to the leadership position, be it in Nigeria’s central government or even in our very own region. Finally brethren, I appeal to you all to join hands in actualizing our dream to build a new nation based on the principles of agreed morals, agreed terms and absolute regional autonomy with the aim to provoke developmental competition. This is what the LNC-driven self-determination quest for our indigenous peoples promises to deliver after the successful conduct of the 2017 scheduled Lower Niger Referendum. Yours truly, Mr. Donald Ekpo</strong></em></li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/egerue-nnamdi/the-man-harold-smith-is-not-new-in-nigerian-history-he-is-o/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4670a8fd-1c51-4fcf-8c57-c9a38442b4c7</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 04:53:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul><li></li></ul>,<img src="https://imgflo.herokuapp.com/graph/vahj1ThiexotieMo/4d90f9f94f90e27e75f3c74da2128dff/croprotate.jpg?cropheight=3600&cropwidth=2159&degrees=0&input=https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/db45df6f-ad27-438e-99ce-a4d3e2d26e74.jpg&x=0&y=0">,<blockquote><ul><li>Photos of clash between security and IPOB/MASSOB Eromosele Ebhomele 3 days ago 38600 Share on Facebook Share on Twitter Send email – Two weeks after a clash between Nigeria’s security operatives and pro-Biafra agitators, photographs of some killed members of the Indigenous People of Biafra (IPOB) and the Movement for the Actualization of the Sovereign State of Biafra (MASSOB) have surfaced. – The photographs show the magnitude of violence that took over a day supposedly to honour late Biafra warlord, Dim Odimegwu Ojukwu. READ ALSO: Biafra killings: We acted in self defence, Nigerian military says Recall that a day after the incident, about 88 members of MASSOB, who were arrested by the Ebonyi state police while they celebrated the day were arraigned. Share on Facebook Share on Twitter A victim of IPOB/police clash Share on Facebook Share on Twitter A victim of IPOB/police clash Share on Facebook Share on Twitter A victim of IPOB/police clash Share on Facebook Share on Twitter A victim of IPOB/police clash Share on Facebook Share on Twitter A victim of IPOB/police clash Share on Facebook Share on Twitter An expended bullet Share on Facebook Share on Twitter A victim of IPOB/police clash Share on Facebook Share on Twitter A victim of IPOB/police clash Share on Facebook Share on Twitter A victim of IPOB/police clash Share on Facebook Share on Twitter A victim of IPOB/police clash Since the clash, the agitators have remained angry accusing the government and its agencies of persecution. They recently described as traitors leaders of the Igbo race who visited President Muhammadu Buhari in the heat of the attack</li></ul></blockquote>,<p>Read more: https://www.naij.com/854906-new-photos-emerge-ipob-massob-members-brutalised-ojukwu-day-celebration.html</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/egerue-nnamdi/photos-of-clash-between-security-and-ipobmassob-eromosele-e/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3d5ef0b9-5e34-4619-8383-35363191cdf3</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 04:49:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/529c8b4a-e195-4fce-8eac-ebcd5e959e80.jpg">,<p>A movement, New Igbo Vision in APC Lagos has called on Igbo people in Lagos State to re-establish the harmonious relationship that existed between them and their hosts in Lagos. The group regretted the acrimony which created the impression that Ndigbo were at loggerheads with their hosts and other ethnic nationalities in Lagos. Addressing a joint press conference in Lagos, the APC Publicity Secretary in Lagos and Eze Ndigbo in Lagos, Messrs Joe Igbokwe and Eze Uche Dimgba respectively, appealed to Igbos in Lagos “who are passionate towards promoting progressive politics and the interest of Ndgbo to key in to this noble idea and join in rebuilding a badly damaged bridge that have hitherto contributed immensely to the huge and monumental successes Ndigbo have made in Lagos.” 29 0 1</p>,<p>Read more at: http://www.vanguardngr.com/2016/04/igbo-apc-calls-peaceful-co-existence-among-ethnic-nationalities-lagos/</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/egerue-nnamdi/d79f7adc-b7ab-497b-be93-923dad6fd6e7/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">d79f7adc-b7ab-497b-be93-923dad6fd6e7</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 11:50:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/fe9ee8f1-336d-4306-aa1f-ad46eda9eed9.jpg">,<p>Abuja – The United Kingdom has announced a further £32 million over the next three years to help deliver basic, life-saving assistance and protection to some of the estimated 7 million people in need of humanitarian assistance due to the conflict in north east Nigeria. The funds will be channelled through the United Nations (UN), the International Committee of the Red Cross (ICRC) and other humanitarian organisations, and will be used to provide support for critical life-saving areas including nutrition, food security, water and sanitation, and protection of civilians affected by the conflict. Apart from the cash, the United Kingdom will also provide the needed technical expertise to Nigeria to drive the programmes and ensure maximum benefit for its people. This was announced in Abuja by the UK Minister for International Development, Nick Hurd, who is in Nigeria for official engagements. Hurd said: “The UK is committed to continuing to help Nigeria to provide humanitarian assistance and protection for people affected by the conflict in north east Nigeria. We welcome Nigeria’s efforts to support the affected population. We look forward to continuing to work with all partners to strengthen the humanitarian effort to reach the most vulnerable, many of whom are in areas that are difficult to access.” Mr. Hurd also noted that the humanitarian needs in north east Nigeria are enormous and growing. A sustained, large-scale Government-led response is needed to meet people’s basic needs and to help them to rebuild their lives once security conditions allow them to return to their places of origin. This new funding is in addition to more than £8.2 million provided by the UK since 2014 to help respond to the life-saving humanitarian needs of people affected by the conflict though violence, displacement, and loss of livelihoods. In addition, the Minister announced a substantial increase of £16.7 million pounds the UK is giving to Nigeria’s rapidly growing solar energy market. The additional funding is in support of a UK sponsored Solar Nigeria Programme that was approved in September 2013 with a budget of £37.1 million pounds. The programme has already supported access to household energy for more than 130,000 people since it was launched in 2014. It has also supported improved healthcare and education for about 185,000 people in Lagos, and earlier this week it won the award for “Outstanding international development project – infrastructure” at the 2016 British Expertise International Awards. The UK’s overall £222 million / year programme in Nigeria improves health and education systems, addresses malnutrition, improves governance, removes the constraints to growth and helps Nigeria better target its own resources. Over 60% of DFID Nigeria’s programme is targeted at northern Nigeria where the needs are greatest.</p>,<p>Read more at: http://www.vanguardngr.com/2016/04/uk-gives-nigeria-32-million-energy-humanitarian-needs/</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/egerue-nnamdi/3b02fe53-efd8-4e7f-ba9c-9f0a7fb49bc1/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3b02fe53-efd8-4e7f-ba9c-9f0a7fb49bc1</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 11:49:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/12d65f02-0e2d-43d9-97a8-7af8d275f69a.jpg">,<p>Governor Ayodele Fayose of Ekiti State has hailed the international community, especially the United States of America and the United Kingdom for joining lovers of democracy in Nigeria to speak out against the All Progressives Congress (APC) government of President Muhammadu Buhari’s use of State security apparatus to oppress opposition. He called on the British Government to investigate the allegation of the use of British foreign aid given to Nigeria to help combat Boko Haram terrorists to fund a witch-hunt against opposition politicians with a view to preventing continuous use of fund belonging to the country wrongly. Ayodele Fayose Speaking through Lere Olayinka, his Special Assistant on Public Communications and New Media, Governor Fayose said the international community must focus attention on Nigeria under President Buhari, saying; “rights of Nigerians are now being trampled upon with impunity.” In its report, the United States Department of States, accused the Nigerian police, DSS and the military of gross abuse of power which include citizens brutality, arbitrary detention,bribery among other scandals Also, the United Kingdom based Telegraph newspaper published this week that hundreds of millions of pounds of British foreign aid given to Nigeria to help combat Boko Haram terrorists was instead being used to fund a witch-hunt against opposition politicians. Governor Fayose, who is presently in Guangzhou, China to attend the 119th China Import and Export Fair otherwise known as the Canton Fair between April 14 and 19, said the United Kingdom Telegraph newspaper was right in its report that the Buhari’s government was using British aid money to target his political opponents, particularly through anti corruption agencies ans the Department of State Services (DSS). He said only the international community could help prevail on President Buhari to respect the rule of law and stop ruling Nigeria like a military dictator. The governor described the United States Department of States report as another vindication of his position on the Buhari-led government’s abuse of the rights of Nigerians, saying; “everything I predicted about Buhari is coming to pass and the international community must assist the country to sustain democracy.”</p>,<p>Read more at: http://www.vanguardngr.com/2016/04/fayose-hails-us-govt-uk-telegraph-reports-on-buharis-witch-hunt-of-opposition/</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/egerue-nnamdi/e98b4164-96c2-417b-80c0-8c0b3e1589c8/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">e98b4164-96c2-417b-80c0-8c0b3e1589c8</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 11:49:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/0b32780b-14d7-4af6-8168-a506bf9f3c9f.jpg">,<p>Federal Government Is Not Treating Igbo People Right - Yerima Lucky Vincent 7 months ago 209687 Share on Facebook Share on Twitter Send email Alhaji Shettima Yerima, an activist and president of the Arewa Youth Consultative Forum (AYCF) in this interview, blows hot about the way the people of the South-eastern part of Nigeria have been treated by the government, and why he thinks the agitation for Biafra is justified even though it is not the best option. The fiery leader of the AYCF also suggests solutions to the crisis. Share on Facebook Share on Twitter Alhaji Shettima Yerima, a activist and president of the Arewa Youth Consultative Forum How did this agitation come this far? Well, it’s been a very long journey and for people like us, it is not surprising. The agitation for Biafra is not news to us because it has been there over time especially since 1966 with what gave birth to the overthrow of the Aguiyi Ironsi government after the killing of some top leaders. The agitation has been there and that was what led to civil war in 1967 when Odimegwu Ojukwu came on board against the state and the reconciliation in the 1970s. Ever since, there had always been one agitation of the other. But the truth of the matter is that nobody is happy about the situation and all of us felt that it would not augur and it is not even in the best interest of this country for any part to secede now. This is a critical and very challenging time. And it is high time we began looking at the issue critically. We are only pretending that Nigeria is a nation, it has never been a nation. We just pray that it would become a nation. There are very fundamental issues that need to be addressed by any government in place and, to do that we must apply the principles of equity, justice and fairness to all. The moment we begin to say this group of people must be dealt with decisively because of their mindset or thinking that they are being marginalised, then there is a problem. READ ALSO: Gowon Slams Biafra Agitators The government must be seen to be doing justice and discussing issues the way they are. If we continue to pretend that things are normal and people are saying they are not normal and are agitating, one day it might not be funny. In as much as we pretend that things are well, you can see this call for Biafra is getting more popular internationally. I pray and I pray the leaders begin to see reasons to look at the issues critically. If they feel they are being marginalised and you underestimate and threaten them by arresting them and incarcerating them, just know that the more you do that, the more they get international and local sympathy. At the end of the day, you would be marvelled at what that amounts to. It could metamorphose into something beyond your expectation. Detention and arrests are not the answers to the issue. Issues must be brought forward for discussion. We must disagree to agree so that we can form a nation. We are not yet a nation. Under international laws which Nigeria is signatory to, the right to see for nationhood is guaranteed. Thus, if people decide that they don’t want to be part of your project, there is nothing you can do about it. Whatever you do is just to buy time. So why don’t you look at the issues the way they are and address them once and for all? This is what I think and it is absolutely my opinion. Those sympathetic to President Muhammadu Buhari believe that the agitation became intense because the average Igbo man does not like a Hausa man being the President. Do you subscribe to this? I do not subscribe to that because before Buhari, there were leaders who came from the Nort. Umar Yar’Adua was from the North and we could see the support from the East until lately when there was this problem of misgivings just before the recent elections. The perception of those in the camp of President Buhari is that the South-east was against him and that he did not get enough votes from the area and so what they bargained for is what they would get. Again, I do not share that perception. This is because this is a democracy where everyone has the right to decide where he wants to stay and if a government is finally formed at the end of the day, that government must be seen to be all-inclusive and carry everybody along irrespective of whether you got votes or not. You must be seen to be more civilised and behave in very civil ways so that we will all feel we are part of this democracy. But where things went wrong and you want to pay back, I do not think that is nationalistic. And when the issue of appointments came up and some positions that should be shared nationally went in one direction as far as we were concerned, some of us raised alarm we did not raise alarm because we don’t enjoy Buhari, but because we know he is human and those who work with him are also human. So where something is going wrong, there is no problem in calling the person to correct it. I do not think it is in the best interest of Nigerians to play politics with things like this because the only reason Buhari is elected is because people gave him mandate to be President of Nigeria and so issues of a section of the country not giving him their votes should not arise. The perception became more glaring and visible because certain things happened in recent times, especially just before the election, after the election and in appointments. It is not because they hate Buhari but certain things have gone wrong and it is better to address them. As long as they remain part of the country, what belongs to them must be given. But where we believe that some parts of the country should be treated as second-class citizens, then we are not doing justice to the nation or that we want the country to survive. This is just the truth of it. There is also this argument that the South-east is not ripe enough to call for secession because there is not particular leader to take them out of the woods. An analyst recently cited the case of South Sudan. What do you think? That they are not mature enough, how is that our problem, the problem of anybody or a section of the country? By law, how is that a problem? It is either you decide to carry them along or if you feel they are a burden to you, then allow them to go. When a child decides that it is time to come out of her mummy’s womb, you can’t stop the child. Oftentimes, we make the mistake of comparing Nigeria with other countries forgetting that we do not share the same culture. We are people from different backgrounds, religions and environments. So I do not share that sentiment. There are also countries that broke and the seceding countries are living on their own. Have you ever seen where a country breaks up and the parts come back together because it was a mistake? It has never happened. So who is afraid in the case of Nigeria? If we cannot do justice to all, then let everyone go peacefully. For me, I do not think the entire North should be held responsible for not allowing the East to go. For me, if they choose to go, so be it. The day we fee tired of this project called Nigeria, we too in the North would say we are going. Let nobody hold anybody to ransom. I only just think going our separate ways is not the best answer, but let’s also begin to decide for them as if we should tell what they want or not. If we cannot bring equity and justice to this table and discuss it, then what is the essence of this pretence? We don’t have to pretend; the country is sick and we need a man who truly believes in the nation to govern it rather than heating it up. And this is where I differ because with the problem at hand like insurgency in the northern part of the country, there should not be any reason to create another monster in another part of the country. Leaders must be seen to be low-headed at this time. Let us not be fooled, this is the best time for leaders to put their heads together and see how things would be solved and appreciate the fact that we come from different backgrounds. Let us not abuse this opportunity. If found wanting, let us address the problem and stop behaving like there is no problem. The moment you begin to say some people should be sidelined, then you are not bargaining for peace. READ ALSO: Radio Biafra Director Granted Bail In resolving this problem now, do you suggest that the report of the last National Conference should be looked into? The report of the National Conference cannot be a reason to start looking at a new Nigeria because even some of us have issues with the Confab and its composition and how it went. This government must be open because if we cannot sit down and discuss it, then there is a problem. This government must be create an atmosphere and engage everyone. I believe a Sovereign National Conference is the answer to this whole thing and there must be no no-go area. People must be allowed to discuss issues. Often, when the issues of national discourse emerge, these mischief makers, these crooks who are 80 percent criminally-minded people at the National Assembly would tell you that they are the ones to discuss them. You cannot be the manager of Nigeria because they voted for you. You cannot just wake up one morning and declare that the sovereignty of the people is now your own. Allow the rightful owners decide how they want to live together and move forward. The constitution we have today is fraud. We challenge the legality of the preamble of the constitution. You cannot be move a country forward where there is problem. The country is sick! We can only buy time, but the day it would escalate, everyone would start running helter-skelter. And I am afraid that the prediction of America that Nigeria would break would not come to pass. Unfortunately, the government of the day believes so much in America. In fact, they even consult America before introducing some local policies to us. You can see how bad it is that after 55 years, Nigeria has not grown enough to decide how we want to govern ourselves. Must we consult America? Why can’t we do our thing our own way? Who even tells you America is in support of Nigerians uniting together? History has shown that so many wars and insurgency around the world have the imprint of America. Can’t we learn from history? Do we want to go into another civil war? I can tell you that if Nigeria goes into another civil war now, we will not survive it.</p>,<p>Read more: https://www.naij.com/618602-federal-government-not-treating-igbo-people-right-yerima.html</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/egerue-nnamdi/federal-government-is-not-treating-igbo-people-right-yerim/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">01f42d0e-8b29-456b-a423-b88ddb365ce3</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 11:48:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/bb49af9c-1120-40d3-9dc7-938b3189c5dd.jpg">,<p>Nigerian army justified the killing pro-Biafra supporters on May 30 – The army claimed that soldiers acted in self-defence when their intervention to restore law and order was resisted – Nigerians took to social media to express their indignation and discontent Share on Facebook Share on Twitter The Nigerian army has recently explained why the soldiers were forced to kill some activists who were commemorating Biafra day in some parts of the country. Justifying the action, Colonel Hamza Gambo, the deputy director of army public relations, 82 Division, Nigerian Army, Enugu, said that soldiers acted in self-defence when their intervention to restore law and order was resisted. “Instructively, troops of 82 Division Nigerian Army as the lead agency of the security agencies had to invoke the extant Rules of Engagement (ROE) to resort to self-defence, protection of the strategic Niger Bridge, prevent re-enforcement of the pro-Biafran members apparently surging ahead from the far side of the strategic Niger Bridge at Onitsha. “In the aftermath of the fire fight that ensued, many of our troops sustained varying degree of injuries. The injured troops are currently receiving treatment at our medical centre. Similarly, five members of MASSOB/IPOB were killed, eight wounded while nine were arrested for due legal actions,” he said. READ ALSO: Biafra massacre: 53 killed, 207 wounded, 403 arrested Following the army’s statement, Nigerians took to social media to express their indignation and discontent.</p>,<p>Read more: https://www.naij.com/846798-acted-self-defence-nigerians-blast-army-justifying-killing-pro-biafra-protesters.html</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/egerue-nnamdi/nigerian-army-justified-the-killing-pro-biafra-supporters-on/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">fdb92868-7013-462b-ae55-da55380e5ce7</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 11:48:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/23b01359-3abb-43bd-9f7a-a0b5955971b3.jpg">,<p>Drink your oil, we would eat our yams, Arewa chieftain tells Niger Delta ON JUNE 5, 20169:07 PMIN NEWS, POLITICSCOMMENTS Senator Joseph Kennedy N Waku, (JKN Waku), the stormy petrel of the Middle Belt was elected senator for the Benue North West Constituency of Benue State, on the platform of the Peoples Democratic Party, PDP in 1999. Not long after she came into national renown following his controversial call for a military coup on the claim that President Olusegun Obasanjo was derailing the democracy project. Since then he has been an unrepentant critic of President Obasanjo, and a major political figure in the North. Waku is not only a chieftain of the ruling All Progressives Congress, APC but also of the Arewa Consultative Forum, ACF. In this interview, he speaks on current national issues. Excerpts: By Joseph Erunke What is your reaction to the renewed insurgency by militants in the Niger Delta? In the first place, what were the offences committed by these people before they were pardoned? Are they not criminals? If I were the president, I would jail them. So, are you ruling out dialogue as proposed by some people as a way of resolving the problem? What kind of dialogue? Let them bring to table what they want. Let them do what they are doing, they will also suffer it. Are they also not suffering when they ruin the economy? Are they not facing the same problem like you and I? They are talking of marginalization today. If you create Biafra today, is Biafra solidly Igbo’s? It’s not. When you go there, you would find a southern minority who will tell you that they don’t want to be part of it, even among the Igbo. Some Igbo will tell you that they don’t want it. If there is definitive kind of discrimination against certain segments of the country, that needs to be addressed because injustice creates dissatisfaction. If there have been injustices against one particular group in this country, let’s address it and not by taking the law into their hands. That is criminality. We are also affected but we want to take it in a matured approach. You cannot go and begin to destroy state apparatus in order to achieve your agitation, it is against the law. I am not in a position to talk about which contract was revoked because I am not involved in that. If those contracts were illegally awarded without going through the due process and the current administration wants to follow due process, what is bad about that? Go and do your investigation on that contract to see whether the old law that qualifies one for such contracts were made. What do you award contracts to militants for? In the first place, the name ‘militant’ is criminality. It is only this country that somebody will come back and say I am a militant and then ‘you award him contract.’ If they claim to be agitators as they are saying, then let them come out with their demands and not by holding the state to ransom. Now, how would you want the government to handle this situation? My advice is that you can’t take government for ransom. If their livelihoods have been damaged considerably by the pipelines and they have nowhere to go, let there be adequate compensation to them. It is not to take laws into their hands. And by the way, let me be honest with you, this is natural resources; nobody owns it and nobody farms it but by virtue of the location that you find yourself. If there is ecological diversification and you need to do something for your livelihood, then you table this issue to the federal government so that there would be amicable resolution Giving the adverse effects of their actions, will it not be better to seek dialogue? What do they need? Let them come out and tell government that ‘this has been our farmland, it has been devastated, we have no land to farm anymore’ and then bring a proposal to the federal government. This is how it should be done than issuing threats. If I were the president, I would have ended that thing by now. How would you have done it? Yes, by closing the whole thing down. Before oil came, didn’t this country exist? So, what are you talking about? We have been blindfolded and Nigeria became so lazy, a nation of cheap money. Before the oil, we had cocoa, we had palm oil, groundnut and pyramid, and those were the things that actually helped to develop the oil. At a point, we in Benue challenged them that okay,’ let them go and drink their oil, we would eat our yams and then see who will survive.’ Read full interview on Monday Vanguard</p>,<p>Read more at: http://www.vanguardngr.com/2016/06/drink-oil-eat-yams-arewa-chieftain-tells-niger-delta/</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/egerue-nnamdi/drink-your-oil-we-would-eat-our-yams-arewa-chieftain-tells/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5366a6df-cc8b-4ddf-a77f-9758d52f024b</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 11:47:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>